Peter Torr Smith

Full-stack mobile & web technologist / developer / analyst / delivery

Wellington phone: 021-451-967

NZ Citizen

email: peter@ptorrsmith.com web: ptorrsmith.com

github: github.com/ptorrsmith linkedIn: linkedin.com/in/ptorrsmith

SKILLS BRIEF

OVERVIEW

I enjoy technology and people, especially when applied to smart business and meaningful services. This could be developing a product or enhancement, configuring a solution, eliciting and reflecting requirements, goals & constraints, helping design a great user experience and application flow, or simply helping others learn, enjoy & create. I love building, solving, and learning new things, but mostly enjoy working with others where we all grow, learn, and create great outcomes. Coffee?

EXPERIENCE

HireThings.com - Developer / CTO for application, platform & mobile-first upgrade (.co.nz / .com.au) Feb **2019** - **Present**

- Upgrade from Rails 2 to Rails 5
- Shift and re-architect onto AWS platform services for hosting and continuous deployment
 - o Elastic Beanstalk, RDS, Elasticache, S3, Route53, EC2, VPC / Security Groups, SES, IAM, Certs
- Upgrade to mobile-first Bootstrap 4.5 front-end
- Product business and UX improvements, Security patches and configuration
- Intern mentoring / training, code reviews, approvals and merges

Ministry of Social Development IT - Web, Mobile, UX and Agile Technologies Manager May 2011 - Sept 2018

- Business Analyst, Agile PM Ruby on Rails projects primarily
- Web Team manager programme and project scoping, costing, delivery
- RFP evaluation and vendor selection, contracts, liaison
- Project pipeline coordinator getting projects ready, scoped, approved
- Mobile & UX Capability Manager mixing internal and external capabilities. MyMSD, MyStudylink.
- Agile Toolsets Design and Operations SAFe, Atlassian Cloud Jira & Confluence

Catalyst IT - Business analyst / project manager / solution designer & dev / client liaison April 2009 - April 2011

- Client liaison, project scoping and solution design / options
- Analyst/PM/co-dev for Drupal CMS, PHP, Moodle, and Ruby on Rails projects
- Facilitation, Testing, client support
- Development and solution configuration / operations
- RFP, pre-sales and solution scoping

HireThings.com - Co-founder, CEO, CFO, Developer

April 2006 - May 2009

- Start-up co-founder, team support and HR
- Developer, analyst, testing, ops Ruby on Rails / AJAX, UX, Wireframing, process design, solution co-design
- Summer of Tech (was Summer of Code) co-leadership
- Everything else needed to keep the dev team and users happy, and the business on track:-)

Peter Torr Smith Profile - 2020

Intergen - Analyst developer and DBA - Microsoft technologies

April 2004 - April 2006

- Microsoft .Net developer (C#, ASP.net). SQL Server DBA, .Net/SAP API dev
- Onsite and offsite client technical support & development
- Web apps, Web Services, WinForms, Windows Services

eCentric - Analyst, Developer and DBA

Dec 2000 - Nov 2002

- Analyst Developer Delphi / .Net eCargo & dairy waste marketplaces
- SQL Server DBA Schema design, stored procedures, triggers
- Early mobile-web (WAP) app design and development
- Onsite and offsite client technical support
- Privilege & fun of working alongside founding Trade Me & AMR teams

Ministry of Agriculture (MAF) - Various business and technical roles

Jan 1994 - Sept 2000

- National management team support governance, legal, finance, programmes
- IT projects coordinator in-house and vendor app / service projects. Nationwide internet rollout
- RFP evaluation and vendor selection, contracts, liaison
- Analyst Developer Y2K upgrades Powerbuilder, SQLWindows winforms, Ingress DB, MSAccess

EDUCATION, TRAINING & DEVELOPMENT HIGHLIGHTS

Udemy - Ruby on Rails 5 Professional - Re-learning Rails 2019

- "Dissecting Ruby on Rails 5". Built ptorrsmith.com built from scratch as a result
- Rails 5, Javascript/JQuery, Bootstrap, PostgreSQL, web-sockets, GIT and Heroku for hosting.

Enspiral Dev Academy - Modern web and mobile development bootcamp Aug - Dec 2018

 HTML, CSS & CSS Frameworks, Javascript backend (node.js) and front-end (React/Redux) & valuable human / soft / personal skills

Scaled Agile Framework (SAFe) - foundation and in practice

2016 - 2018 - in-house and online

- Enterprise application of SAFe and agile toolsets evolution 2016-18 ('SAFe on Jira, Confluence')
- Formal SAFe training, exams and certification for SAFe 2017

MSP - Managing Successful Programs - Foundation and Professional 2015

Better Business Cases (BBC) - Training, Enterprise representation, and exam - Foundation 2013

PRINCE2 - 'Projects in Controlled Environments' - Foundation and Professional 2011

Certified Scrum Master - agile planning, delivery and team support 2011

Microsoft Certified DBA - SQL Server DBA certification 2001 & 2006

Post graduate Diploma - Information Sciences - Extramural and on-campus studies **2001 - Massey University**

Bachelor of Commerce - Management, Accounting, Marketing and Finance 1989 - Auckland University

INTERESTS

Mobile, smart & connected technologies (IoT)
Economics
Fermentation
Cooking
Roasting coffee
Swimming
Mountain Biking
Hiking/walks
Global social and tech trends
Campervanning
Predator Free NZ (volunteer)
Helping others learn / mentoring

REFERENCES

On request